here. Um, but we'll let you start us
off.
>> All right. Uh, good afternoon. It's
great seeing everybody. I see a lot of
familiar faces on here. Sup, Herby,
Nate, Sam. You know, I'm not, uh,
uh, ignoring anybody else, but those are
some familiar faces that I've seen. But,
uh, first and foremost, I just want to,
uh, thank, uh, the Chicago Bears
organization. And uh it was a great run,
a great season, uh thanking George Macy,
the president, obviously the whole
entire Macy family. Uh the team
president, Kevin Warren, I think a lot
of people are familiar with the name
Kevin Warren because he was once here
once upon a time. Uh Ted Cruz, also like
to send a special shout out to Ryan
Poles and head coach Ben Johnson. You
talking about great people. uh a great
organization and it felt like home and
that was the beauty of it. It was real
real tough making this decision, but you
know, uh it was an opportunity to come
home and it was like leaving home. But
now, you know, if Big Red ever picks up
the phone, that's the only person that
you'll say, "Hey, you know what? It may
be time to return home because he's uh
given me this opportunity." But more
than anything, it was um
very, very tough uh after exactly what
we just went through. But more than
anything, I'm fired up about this
opportunity. I'm looking forward to it
and it's it's it's time to get back in
the saddle. With that said,
>> uh I'm all ears. Let's hit it.
>> Thank you, coach. We'll start first with
Sam McDow. Go ahead, Sam.
>> Hey, Eric. How's it going?
>> What's going on, Sam? How you doing?
>> Good. Good to see you.
>> Good to see you as well.
>> I'm just wonder I got a couple things
for you. I wonder first of all, how much
have you had a chance to maybe dig into
what the Chiefs offense was last year?
And if so, what were your impressions?
>> You know what? I really haven't had an
opportunity to dig in and really study
it like I want to. Every now and then, I
would pick up, you know, a few ideas or
a few plays here and there, but I really
haven't had a chance to dig in like I
want to. I'm going to spend this time
doing that during this uh period just to
figure out uh the good, the bad, and the
ugly, and the indifferent. And but uh
I'm excited about the opportunity.
Obviously uh looking forward to uh
getting back to work with some of these
guys and ideally just getting re
reaclimated with the staff.
>> I don't want to just focus on the bad
and the ugly on on that, but I do wonder
and I think I I' know what where the
answer goes with this, but I'm still
curious of your response of just your
comfort level when you do see the bad
and the ugly in your conversations with
coaches about pointing out the flaws
that you might see.
>> Well, I mean that's why we get paid.
We're coaches, right? It's our job to
come up with answers. So, we got to make
sure that we can give solutions to the
answers and making sure that uh that we
resolve it. Uh we got a great coaching
staff, got great people. I feel like uh
I'm back in in in with family, you know,
and uh so we all are very familiar with
each other. So, we'll sit down and
figure everything out together.
>> We'll go next to Nate Taylor. Go ahead,
Nate.
>> Hello, Eric. Good to see you. I have uh
two questions as well.
>> Yes, sir.
>> My first is I'm sure you heard Patrick's
comments about wanting new ideas. From
your perspective in the past three
years, how much you think those
experiences will help you get to maybe
presenting new ideas, not only to
Patrick, but Andy and the rest of the
offensive staff? Uh, I think it's it's
always good because I've had an
opportunity to to learn a few things and
uh obviously open up my mind just to how
to view things from a different point of
view and uh and it's great, but on top
of that, we got to make sure that we're
getting down to what is best for us when
it's all said and done with. So yes, it
anybody can present an idea, but more
importantly, we need to make sure first
and foremost that we're taking a look at
anything that we need to to continue to
improve upon or continue working with
and making sure that we're getting all
the answers first with that and then
just figure out where do we need to go
from there. But it's day one. Um we'll
figure all that out at some point in
time. But I will say this, I'm fired up
and excited just to have this
opportunity to be in the building and
just having these discussions.
>> And secondly, Eric, um, have you had a
chance to talk to Patrick? Have you had
a chance to talk to Travis? And just
what is your, I guess, initial reactions
of getting back working with them, uh,
obviously for next season. You know
what? I've had just a a a small minimum
conversation with both and they all have
been great. But more than anything, it's
just the excitement of just reuniting.
You know, it was just like when I came
here, we came out here uh and we played
them in the preseason. It was great
seeing those guys, you know, cuz I
haven't seen them in years. And so, it
just feels good just to sit down and
have conversations with guys. And to be
honest, I have not talked any football
or anything. is just the excitement of
just seeing each other, asking how
they're doing, and making sure
everything is is good moving forward.
But is the excitement high? Yes. Am I
fired up? Yes. Do I respect the hell out
of both those guys? Yes. So, I'm looking
forward to to to getting back in the
grind and chopping wood with them.
>> We'll hear from Herby Tobi next. Herby
>> coach, welcome back to Kansas City, man.
>> How we doing, Herby? What's that?
>> Hey, I'm doing well, thanks. I got two
questions here.
>> It's sort of a followup to what Nate
asked you about offering that creative
voice to this offense, but
>> the opportunity to kind of spread your
wings over the last few years as an
offensive play caller in Washington and
UCLA. How do you think that helped
>> develop you to be more of a creative
voice on the staff?
>> You know what? I think it's it's helped
me in a number of ways cuz when you're
doing it on your own, you got to find
creative ways to to to implement a
system. On top of that, you learn a lot
about yourself, you know, the good, the
bad, and the ugly because all ideas are
not bad ideas. We just need to be
receptive to them. And so, just the
dynamic of working with people, learning
how to communicate and articulate your
plan and getting them to buy in, I think
all that helps. And I think any
experience that you've had, whether it's
good or bad, it's it's it's all
something that we can learn from. And so
with that said, I've learned a lot over
the years. I've learned a lot about
myself. And uh I'm just excited, you
know, just to to get started. And
obviously today is day one, but I want
to make sure day two, three, four, and
five [laughter] that we hit the ground
running, you know, uh with all this
excitement and all this energy that's
being created.
You mentioned hitting the ground running
and this is my last question. Obviously,
given your background coaching running
backs, how involved do you see yourself
as the offensive coordinator with
energizing this run game?
>> I I let me just say this. First and
foremost, we we obviously have a
tremendous staff and uh obviously uh you
know uh with Coach Reed, we're going to
figure out what things that we need to
do move moving forward as far as making
sure we're getting the right people in
the building. But when it's all said and
done with, we we're going to make sure
that we can do the things that we do
best. We have one of the better O
lineman coaches here in the industry and
coach heck. He does an outstanding job
with those guys up front and then just
having an impact and just making sure
that we're doing the things that we can
do that's going to help us moving
forward. So yes, have I been exposed to
a number of run schemes? Yes. All right.
At the end of the day, we got to make
sure that we're doing what is best for
us moving forward. And I think that's
just the general overall plan.
We'll go next to Nick Jacobs. Nick?
>> Yeah, and I'll have a followup, please.
Um, Eric, for you, whether it was
Deshawn, Ron Rivera, Ben Johnson, or
other coaches on staff, how did they
help make you a better teacher um to the
players? Uh, I think more than anything
just sitting down and having that
discussion with them, you know, because
when you're working with people who's
not familiar with what you do, it's
basically you're selling your idea and
your thoughts, okay? You're selling that
game plan to those coaches, getting them
to buy in. And those are things that uh
not tough, but what it does, it gives
you an opportunity to articulate your
playing clear and and just basically
defining it and painting a picture for
them so they can see it and see it how
it comes to fruition and everything. And
so that's one thing that uh that I would
say that has helped me moving forward.
But more than anything, just the ability
just to sit down and communicate with
players as well because every person,
every player is different. Okay? It's
all about still establishing the right
relationships and getting to know the
people that you're working with. If
anything, I think over the years, you
still want to spend that amount of time.
But I think that's something that I can
do even a a much better job of is just
getting to know the people and on top of
that making sure that I'm establishing
myself within the culture as well and
just not blending in but also making
sure that I can be the right fit and
implementing the things that I want to
implement as well.
>> And then speaking of culture, you got to
go to three different ones that were
different than what you got to
experience for over a decade in Kansas
City. How did that kind of help you
maybe appreciate some things here but
also be like, "Hey, if I get a chance in
the future, I want to implement this."
>> Just what you said, I think it's exactly
that because of, you know, because of
the success, you always have a tendency
of wanting to do it the way that you
know it uh to be done. But on top of
that, there's different ways to to to to
to
game plan everything. And I and I think
more than anything I just gained a
diverse deal of wealth over the years
from three good men who were head
coaches that have an approach that you
know what it's not bad. These are great
ideas that I think that moving forward
that you know at some point in time can
can uh implement you know uh as we move
forward. I'm sorry but uh it was a
unique experience a very unique
experience but on top of that a very
educating one as well.
We have time for just a couple more.
We'll go next to Vah Gregorian. Vahi.
>> Hey, Eric. Welcome back. Um,
>> yeah. How you doing?
>> Good. Good. Uh, a couple things related
to what you've been speaking about. When
when you say that about learning about
yourself, I realize it's hard to sum
this all up, but what do you feel like
these last couple years have made you
learn about yourself? And then Kelsey,
I'll just have one quick followup. Uh,
more than anything, you you develop
patience.
uh you develop a broad view on things.
Uh it forces you to go back and maybe uh
uh look at things a little bit
different. All right? And how you
approach everything because just because
it worked here doesn't necessarily mean
it's going to work somewhere else
somewhere else. And so you just want to
make sure that you're fitting in all
right within the environment that you're
you're working with. And one thing, you
know, anybody can call plays, but you
got to make sure that you are doing what
is best for those players, all right, in
that particular time because the talent
level may not equate to what you may
have worked with in the past, but this
talent level can do some things that are
different. And that's one thing that
that you learn and and it's it's a
valuable lesson because it's something
that will help you, but it's humbling as
well. [clears throat] But, you know,
it's very educating. And let me just say
this. Um, I lost my train of thought
there. Excuse me. I got a lot of stuff
on my mind. But, uh, I'm fired up about
the opportunity of being here, but
I I'm sorry, my phone was buzzing. I
apologize.
>> Not at all. Just just the the last part
is simply do it's probably hard to
describe this, but how much do you feel
like you're the same person who left
here versus how much you might feel like
you're a bit different now? Well, I'll
say this. There's some things about me
that have changed, but more than
anything, EB is EB. We will still be
disciplined and detail in everything and
how we handle our business. There's a
standard of performance. there's a
standard of excellence that'll be
expected, but on top of that, there's
been a great deal of wealth that I've
learned, you know, through the good and
through the bad. And the thing that I
appreciate has just helped me to grow
into this role and have this opportunity
to be in this uh this situation again.
And thank you.
>> We'll go quickly to Matt Derek. Matt,
>> hey coach, it's good to see you again.
Welcome back to City.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Doing well. Hope you are as well. uh
when you look back at your five years as
as offensive coordinator here, what what
stands out to you? What are the what are
the memories and what do you feel like
were the hallmarks of those five years
of uh really sustained success that you
had?
>> You know what I think uh obviously
there's a number of things that you can
look back upon. Um I mean hell, you can
look back at the first Super Bowl. You
know, everybody always asks me the
question, what was that the deal about
the Wasp play? You know, what took place
when we were miked up? Uh, you know,
people always ask me that question and
and everybody wants to know, you know,
what type of guy uh Pat Mahomes is or
what what makes Travis Kelce uh ticks.
But here's the beauty of it, I think,
more than anything is just watching
these guys grow over the years and just
watching them become the men that they
have become and watching their success
from afar. You know, that's what I'm
proud of more than anything. not the
things that we've accomplished
throughout that time, but the things
that they have accomplished since then.
You know, watching them grow as men,
watching them become uh uh family men.
And uh I think more than anything,
that's important because the
relationships that you build, they'll
outlast anything. And these young men,
I'm just very proud of. And I'm just
proud that I've had an opportunity to
work with them.
>> We'll go to our final question here with
Pete Sweeney. Pete.
>> Uh, hey Erica. Congratulations. Uh, you
mentioned that that big red calls, one
big red calls you pick up. I just was
wondering if you could describe how this
uh came about from from your
perspective. I know that you finished
very recently with Chicago, but just how
it how it all um happened.
>> Well, um,
to be quite honest, it just happened.
[laughter]
You know, we were playing in the
playoffs and uh, unfortunately we came
up short. The next day I get a phone
call. Big Red is calling and um
obviously there was some tough
conversations having uh with the head
coach and uh with our players, but
you know, it was it was great having
that opportunity to work in Chicago.
Great having that opportunity to work
with coach Ben Johnson who's a a hell of
a coach, was going to have a great deal
of success as well. And uh it was great
having that opportunity to working with
that organization. But having this
opportunity to come back and uh be put
in this chair with Coach Reed, that was
just something that it it's tough to
pass upon, you know. So, uh with all
that taking place, I'm excited. I'm
fired up. Uh it was one of them deals
that happened fast and I'm looking
forward to it. Um I just drove in
yesterday. [laughter]
I I waited out the storm, so I'm here
now. I'm uh you know going off a few
hours of sleep, but more than anything,
I'm just excited and fired up about the
opportunity. I feel like a kid in a
candy store. You know, I don't know if
you guys can hear the nervous energy in
my voice. I've just excitement.
>> Coach Benemy, we appreciate the time and
we're glad you got here safely in the
weather. We'll let you get back to it.
>> All right. Thank you very much.